本字幕由不着调字幕组原创翻译 严禁一切商用 禁止二次上传
更多请关注微博：BZD不着调字幕组  招新测试QQ群 ：160676806
m 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 4 0 9 0 13 b 4 13 9 13 13 13 b 13 9 13 4 13 0
总监：雪宝     特效：肉丸     后期：浅浅粉
校对：JessieJessie亮晶晶   翻译：珏  十草W
BZD
他是我见过最无情 最自私的人
He's the most unsympathetic, selfish person I've ever met
我是绝对不会碰他的
I would never touch him
我和你说过我不想发生婚前性行为的吧
I told you I won't have sex before I get married, right?
天哪
Jesus!
我哥有精神病
My brother is a complete psychopath
精神病
Psychopath?
告诉我你没有和我哥上床
Tell me you didn't sleep with my brother
我不知道
I don't know
你没和尼克上床
You didn't sleep with Nico
但他拍了我的照片 裸照
But he took pictures of me.Naked pictures
我告了他
I reported him
我刚去地下室了，
看起来那里好像有
人住并睡在那里。
那里有床垫 被子
和其他的，你知道
是怎么回事么？
你的打算是什么
What's the plan?
因为你哥哥卑鄙 你就要跑去伦敦当混蛋吗
you gonna go around London being an asshole because ur brother is mean
因为你女朋友欺骗了你
Because your girl lied to you?
羞耻
第二集季终
星期六 11:23
BGM：God Don't Leave Me(feat HighasaKite)
今天我们就躺在床上吧
We should just lie here today
好
Okay
怎么了
What's wrong?
别停
Don't stop
我需要点空间 好吗
I need some space, okay?
你不需要
You don't need space
我认真的
Dead serious
我尊重你
I respect you
现在你要尊重我
Now you have to respect me
我十三岁的时候 和人上过床
I had...sex when I was thirteen
他和我发生关系之后态度就变得很差
And the guy I had sex with behaved really shitty afterwards
所以在春天的时候 也不全是因为那件事
So in the spring...It was not just because of that
有很多原因
Lots of stuff
但那以后我有点
But then I got kind of...
心理阴影
sick
所以我可能只是
So I'm probably just...
害怕那样的事情会再度发生
Scared that something like that will happen again
嘿
Hey you
我真的非常抱歉
I'm really damn sorry
尼克做了那样的事
For what Nico has done
但那不是你的错
But it wasn't your fault
没发生什么严重的事情 而且他会被判罪的
Nothing serious happened, and he'll be convicted
不是很好吗
Isn't that good?
挪威有法律制度
We have a legal system in Norway
我们只需要相信法律是公正的
We just have to trust that the legal system is fair
所以你不用去杀他
So you don't have to kill him
你没有杀了他 对吧
You didn't kill him, did you?
我还没有见过他
I haven't seen him
我去伦敦了
I went to London
他在奥斯陆吗
Is he in Oslo?
不知道
Don't know
我还没有回过家
I haven't been to the apartment
这段时间住在我们公寓地下室的人是你吗
Is it you who has been living in our basement?
确实有人住在这里的地下室
There really is someone who's living in our basement
好可怕
So damn creepy
我知道
I know!
我住在克里斯家 之后也会继续住在他那的
I stayed with Chris.I'll continue to stay with Chris
你也可以住在这里
You can live here, too
但是你偶尔
But you have to
也得回家一趟
Go back to the apartment sometime
我不能见到尼克
I can't meet Nico
我可以和你一起去
I can come with you
我可不怕他
I'm not scared of him
星期天 16:52
有人吗
Hello?
他不在家
He's not here
你现在打算怎么办
What do you wanna do now?
离开
Leave again
-你不想在这儿待一会吗   -为什么
- Don't you want to be here for a while?   - Why should I?
你得夺回你的房子
You have to take back your apartment
我不能住在这里
I can't live here
你
You
你现在可以逃避 但你不能躲你哥一辈子
You need to give in now.You can't run from ur brother rest of your life
你必须面对他
You just have to face him
你必须直视他 并且告诉他 他是个彻头彻尾的失败者
You have to look him in the eye and tell him he's a fucking loser
结束这一切
Be done with it
事情没有那么简单
That's not how it works
如果我现在见到他 我不知道自己会做出什么事
I don't know what I would have done if I had met him now
你要搬去哪儿
Where will you move to?
我会再买一间新的公寓
I'll buy a new apartment
你有钱吗
You have money for that?
我会搞定的
It'll work itself out
所以你的解决办法就是买一套新房子
So your solution is to buy a new apartment?
嗯
Yes
你想和我一起住吗
Do you want to move in with me?
说想
Say yes
威廉
William
你就不能有一次不去管对错 只做你想做的事吗
Can you not for once stop what's right and wrong, just do what you want
好
Okay
我们要住在一起啦
We'll move in together!
我们要住在一起了
We'll move in together
继续啊
Don't stop
你不用停
You don't need to
这是什么
What's that?
威廉
William!
法庭传票 六月三号 星期五 下午三点
Summon for interrogation.Friday, 3rd of June.At 3 o' clock
为什么
Why?
因为我用瓶子砸了那家伙的脑袋 有人录了视频
Because I smashed a bottle on that guy's head.There's a video of it
星期一 11:25
怎么我一来你们就不说话了
Why did you guys stop talking when I came?
你有收到警方的通知吗
Have you received a letter from the police?
没有
No
你们收到了吗
Have you?
我们被传唤询问巴士派对那天晚上打架的情况
We've been summoned for questioning about the fight
他们还通知了我们的父母
on the night of the bus party.They called our parents
-我妈训我了  -我也被训了
- Mom snapped completely  - Mine too
为什么我没被传唤
Why was I not summoned?
可能因为你在警察来之前就走了 他们记下了我们的名字
Probably because you left before the police arrived.They took our names
又碰巧在网上看到了那个视频
They came across the video on the internet.
就开始调查这件事
The police has reported the case themselves
但你没有被传唤是件好事
But it's good that you weren't summoned
这样你就不用出面指证威廉了
It prevents you from having to testify against William
你们会指证他吗
Will you guys testify against William?
我们能怎么办 我们不能对警察说谎啊
What should we do? We can't lie to the police
我们可以拒绝回答
We can refuse to say anything
对 我们有权保持沉默
Yeah, we have the right to remain silent
反正他们不能只凭那个视频就给威廉定罪
They can't convict him based on just that video anyway
那个视频像素低 也没对好焦
The quality is bad and it's unfocused
我们必须想清楚
We really have to think this through carefully
他可能因为这件事坐六个月的牢 我查过的
He could go to prison for six months.I googled it
这件事是由威廉做的好事引起的
This all started when William did something good
怎么回事
How so?
冬天的时候 威廉打了一个
In the winter William beat up a Yakuza guy
骂克里斯前女友伊本贱婊子的小混混
for calling Iben, Chris' ex-girlfiriend, a cheap whore
为了报复 那个小混混打了入侵者的三个人
To avenge himself he beat up three Penetrator guys
威廉什么也没干
And William did nothing
他们打了约纳斯
They beat up Jonas
所以克里斯和伊萨克准备在巴士派对那天晚上教训那些人
Chris and Isak planned to beat up Yakuza on the night of the bus party
威廉毫不知情
William didn't know anything about it
但最终却要他为此负责
But he ended up having to take it
我们不能把故事经过告诉警察吗
Can't we tell them this story?
我认为这样做没有用
I don't think that's how it works
他们只关心是谁拿瓶子砸了别人的头
They're only interested in who threw the bottle at someone's head
威廉为什么要用瓶子砸人 娜拉
Why did William smash that bottle, Noora?
-为什么   -嗯
- Why?   - Yes
他觉得那个混混打了他的好朋友
He smashed it because he felt it was his fault
是因为他的错
That Yakuza beat up his best friend
他对他爱的人非常忠诚
He's extremely loyal to the ones he loves
所以他才这样做
So he did it because
他不想让大人承担责任
He doesn't entrust this responsibility with adult people, because
毕竟从来没有为他负责任的大人
There has never been an adult who has taken responsibility of him
而且他不能很好地控制自己的情绪
He also has a little trouble controlling his mind
如果你们能这么说就好了
It'd be great if you said that, too
审讯的时候我们就保持沉默吧
I say we shut our mouths at the questioning
我同意
I agree
行 就这么做
Okay, let's do it
你觉得伊萨克和约纳斯会说什么吗
Do you think Isak and Jonas will say anything?
不会 是威廉帮了他们
No, it was William who helped them
而且约纳斯讨厌警察
Jonas doesn't even like the police
唯一会毁掉一切的就是那些混混出来指证他
The only thing that could fuck up everything, is if Yakuza testifies against him
星期二 16:15
艾斯科尔德
Eskild?
Eskild!
怎么了
What?
我不知道你把谁带来住在地下室里
I don't know who you've got living down in our basement
但不能继续下去了 楼下的住户跟我抱怨了
But it has to stop.We've gotten complaints from our downstairs neighbors
我不知道这件事 不是我
I don't know anything about it.It's not me
是蒂托吗 还是尼托
Is it Tito? Or Nito?
我什么都不知道 可能是琳
I don't know anything about it.It could be Linn
这是你的床单
It's your bedding
不是
No, it's not
你还知道哪张床单是我的 你这跟踪狂
You know what bedding is mine? Stalker
艾斯 我是这个屋子里唯一一个洗床单的人
Eskild, I'm the only one who washes bedding in this house
如果没有我 你的床单上全部都是结块的陈年精液了
Had it not been for me, your bedding would be full of stiff, old cum
什么
What's this?
你刚才是说了结块的陈年精液吗
Did you just say stiff, old cum?
哇
Wow!
有进步啊 女孩
Way to go, girl!
污啊
Dirty
艾斯 别转话题
Eskild, don't change the subject now!
是因为威廉吧
It's because of William
不是因为威廉
No, it's not because of William!
就是的 我能看出来 你的思想更“性”感了
Yes, it is I can see it in you. You think in a more sexual way
干得好啊 威廉 我给你鼓掌 能让一个人焕然一新
Good job, William Applause! From one guy to another
让你“性”潮澎湃
He got them juices flowin', Willy!
靠 艾斯 闭嘴
Fuck, Eskild Shut up!
你们啪啪啪了没
Did you guys have sex?
没有
No!
你们赶紧的 看你现在简直欲火焚身了 救命
You're gonna have it now! You're so horny now, help!
你看过小黄片了吗
Didn't you see the video?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me now?
打开谷歌 搜索"Skogtur"
"Skogtur" On Google Search for "Skogtur"
-你可以和威廉一起看 当作前戏  -再见 艾斯
- You can watch it with William.Foreplay   - Bye, Eskild
别再让人住地下室了
Stop having people live in the basement
艾斯
Eskild!
Skogtur 干嘛
Yes? "Skogtur"
帮我和蒂托问声好 顺便让他找个新地方住
Say hi to Tito and tell him to find himself a new place to live
好的
Yeah
你要是看那视频的话告诉我一声 我也好久没看了
let me know if you're gonna watch that video.I haven't seen it for a long time
-能一起看的话就太爽了   -再见
- It's quite cool to watch it together   - Bye!
星期四 20:15
m 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 4 0 9 0 13 b 4 13 9 13 13 13 b 13 9 13 4 13 0
你从哪儿拿到的这号码
伊娃从伊本那儿要来的,伊
本是问那家伙的前女友要的
好吧 祝我好运吧
-嘿   -怎么了
- Hey you   - Hm?
你名字里为什么有两个O
Why do you actually write Noora with two O's?
别人都不这么取名字的
No one else does it
你知道薇尔德吧
Eh, you know Vilde
我知道薇尔德
Yes.I know Vilde
好吧
Yeah
她刚才把那混混的电话号码发给我了
She just sent me the number of the Yakuza guy
好吧 你想用它来干什么
Okay, what are going to do with it?
没有 我只是想
No, I just thought that
也许你可以打给他
Maybe you could call him
我为什么要打给他
Why should I?
那样你就可以问他能不能在审讯的时候什么都别说
So that you could've asked him if he couldn't say anything in the interrogation
不要
No
威廉
William!
我认真的
Seriously!
拜托
Please
别这样
Forget it
但是你听我说
Yeah but listen!
所有人都会保持沉默的
Everyone is keeping their mouth shut
你的人 伊萨克和约纳斯 还有我的朋友 每个人
Your guys, Isak and Jonas, and my friends.Everyone!
如果你不把他们干的事说出来
If you don't say anything about all that they did
他们也不会把你的说出去的
they won't say anything about what you did either
娜拉
Noora
不要
No
你别管
Forget it
就是这样
Done
他拒绝打电话 所以这事黄了
He refuses to call, so that's fucked
不是吧 简直是个白
痴 他干嘛非得这么
清高 要坐六个月的
牢呢！！！！
就是
的呀.....
不过你可以打给他
你可以读给我听吗
Do you want to read to me?
*挪威戏剧家 诗人
易卜生吗
Ibsen?
拜托啦
Please?
为什么
Why?
因为我很想听易卜生的故事
Because I'm excited to hear Ibsen's story
故事 易卜生的故事
Story? The story of Ibsen?
-没错  -故事里的易卜生
- Yes   - The Ibsen of the story?
-什么都没有  -这里有好多页呢
- There's nothing here   - There's lots of pages here
你就读吧
Just read 'em
读里面的话吗
Read 'em words?
*故事主人公与娜拉同名 但名字中少一个O
《玩偶之家》
A Doll's House
《玩偶之家》吗
A Doll's House?
谁在乎啊
Who cares?
-三幕戏剧   -1879年
- Three-act play   - 1879
不
No
你真可爱
You're cute
没错 这倒是实话
Yeah, that's true
星期五 18:44
m 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 4 0 9 0 13 b 4 13 9 13 13 13 b 13 9 13 4 13 0
你好 你不认识我
但是4月29日的斗殴我也在场
我只想说只要你什么都不说
当时在场都不会把发生的事情说出来
我们什么都不会说
哈喽
Hello
怎么样
How did it go?
挺好的
It went fine
可是你进去了四个钟头 他们说什么了
Yeah, but you were there for four hours.What did they say?
你感觉他们有很多对你不利的证据吗
Did you get the impression they have a lot of evidence against you?
我承认了
I confessed
为什么 你不能 你为什么要这么做
Why did you.You can't. Why did you do that?
我也不知道 或许是因为你说的话吧
Hell, do I know? Maybe it's because of what you said
我说什么了 我让你别胡说 这才是我说的
What I said?! I said you shouldn't say shit.That's what I said
你说的尼克的事
The stuff about Nico
你说我们应该相信公平公正的法律制度
That we should believe in and trust that we have a fair legal system
我选择去相信它
I chose to trust it
或者
Alternatively
我也可以选择不信它
I could have chosen to not trust it
乖乖闭嘴什么也不说
And just kept my mouth shut about it
可是那样的话我可能会杀了尼克
But then I'd nearly killed Nico
你懂我的意思吗
If you get what I mean
那现在会怎么样呢
But what will happen now?
几周后我就要上法庭了
I have to go to court in a few weeks
我可能会进监狱
I might have to go to prison
那你现在想干什么 趁你还是个自由身
What do you want to do now? While you're still free?
我现在想干什么呢
What do I want to do now?
-我知道我想干什么了  -什么
- I know what I want to do  - What?
我现在想干的事 就是开一个超大的派对
What I want to do now, is to have a really big party
尽情地疯
Where we get completely wasted
我们到处爬来爬去
We'll just crawl around
好啊
Okay
-好   -好
- Yeah   - Yeah
你觉得在哪儿开好呢 我那儿吗
Where do you think that's gonna happen? At my place?
还是去我那该死的公寓吧
We may as well go back to that damn apartment
BGM:I Gotta Feeling(feat Black Eyed Peas)
我要下单了啊 还有没有人想要
I'm ready to order.If there's someone else who wants to
伊娃
Eva!
你得认识一下伊萨克
You have to meet Isak!
-嗨 艾斯   -伊萨克
- Hi! Eskild - Isak
-还有约纳斯  -嗨 艾斯
- And Jonas   - Hi! Eskild
我和他一起住
I live with him
-我们同居  -不是 我们和其他舍友住在同一个房子里
- We live together   - No.we live in a house with roommates
我们同居
We live together
约纳斯在说娜拉撞见吹箫的事情
[Jonas talking about Noora's story of the BJ action ]
-真的吗  -没错
- Huh? - Yes!
什么吹箫
What BJ action?
哪天 星期六吗
What day? On Saturday?
不 是很久之前的事了
No! It was a really long time ago
我每次被吹完就都不会记得了
I can't remember everytime I get sucked off
是真的 如果我们很爽的话 我就不会再想这件事了
It's true. If we have fun, I won't think about it anymore the day after
这难道不是很好
Isn't that a good philosophy?
-做好你自己的事   -没错
- Do your thing! - Yeah!
说起那件夹克 我知道她
Speaking of that jacket.I know she
我知道不是她做的 但是她在那个工厂做缝纫
I know she's not the one who created it, but she sews at the factory
我在亚洲的时候见过她
I met her when I was in Asia
-你很酷  -谢谢夸奖
- You look so cool!  - Thank you
BGM:2AM(feat Astrid S＆Matoma)
我喜欢你站在那儿
看着我
对吧
其实你很讨厌派对
我没有“讨厌”它
我们可以不用呆在这
去你那轻松下,
怎么样
要的
哦不 ，那并不是我想
你想要什么
BGM:I Wanna Fuck You(feat Snoop Gogg＆Akon)
克里斯出去
Chris. Out
你认真的吗
Are you serious now?
出去 马上
Out. Now
老兄
Bro!
我知道我应该问你是否准备好了 但我现在不想管这么多了
I know I should ask you if you're ready, but I don't care now
那就闭嘴
So shut up
我的天哪 卡斯伯
Oh my god! Kasper!
卡斯伯
Kasper!
这里没有人吗
Is there no life here?!
我觉得我做了一件蠢事
I think I did something stupid
什么意思
What do you mean?
我发了一条短息给那个混混
I sent a message to the Yakuza guy
我就知道你会这么做
I knew you were going to do it
你不生气吗
You're not mad?
换做是我也会这么做的
I would have done the same
你要搬出来的话 艾斯和琳他们会说什么
What will Eskild and Linn say when you tell them you're moving out?
我不敢告诉他们 你来说
I'm scared to say it. You have to say it
好吧
Okay
天哪 肯定会顺利的
My god, it'll go well for sure
他们只要找到人搬进去住就行了
They just have to find someone else who can live in the room
腰带不错啊
Oh, cool belt!
是吗
Is it?
你是说这腰带好看吗
Are you taking the credit for that belt?
-是你的吗  -对 是伊萨克的
- Is it yours?   - Yes, it's Isak's
哦 好吧
Ah, I see
实际上他所有好看的衣服都是我的
All his coolest clothes are actually mine
BGM:Young Forever(feat Jay-Z＆Mr.Hudson)
m 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 0 0 0 0 0 b 0 4 0 9 0 13 b 4 13 9 13 13 13 b 13 9 13 4 13 0
SKAM 爱 你们
更所请关注微博
BZD不着调字幕组
BZD 爱 你们
有奖问答（最后一题）
Q3：William和Chris的Russ巴士名？
关注@BZD不着调字幕组
参与方式：
在相应集数的微博下回答
具体请关注字幕组微博
即可有机会获得小礼物